Guide to the Paul L. Ross Papers 1933-1978 MS 3138
New-York Historical Society
- State of New Jersey v. Gail Madden (2 folders), 1970, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
  Draft filing and arguments, and correspondence between Ross, Gail (Madden) Glenn, her public defender, and others related to Ross's involvement as an attorney in her appeal of her 1974 murder conviction (at retrial of a 1968 conviction).
- Nova University, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Concerns Ross's proposal for a seminar on trial practice.
- Florida Alliance Against Repression, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Printed materials from the organization.
- Miscellaneous Writings, 1933-1972 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Includes Ross's published article "Lawyers and Judges in Hebrew Jurisprudence" (1933); prospectus for a book with the tentative title of "City Hall, New York" (circa 1955); Published article in The Nation "New York: Captive Giant" (1955); book review of Ann Fagan Ginger's "The Relevant Lawyers" (1973); and published articles in "Liberty" on conspiracy law repression (1970) and on a draft bill to bar unconstitutional data collection (1972).
- Miscellaneous Correspondence and Other Documents, 1964-1978 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Holds four documents: acknowledgement from Councilman J. Raymond Jones of Ross's congratulatory letter (1964); letter and clipping from Mark Ptashne of Harvard regarding his trip to Laos and Vietnam (1970); warm and friendly letter from Toshi Seeger referring to, among other things, Pete Seeger's current concert tour in Spain and on to Cuba (January 21, 1971); and Ross's NY Times obituary (1978).